Luis Furtado Araujo

Software Engineer

🕙 linkedin.com/in/luis-furtado- 🔷 github.com/luis-furtado

I am a software engineer with 7 years of experience across the entire software development lifecycle—from product definition and requirement analysis to backend and frontend development, infrastructure, architecture, automated testing, and software quality. Currently, I focus on technical leadership and full-stack development, with the goal of driving projects to success by balancing scalability, performance, and maintainability.

RECENT WORK HISTORY

ARCO EDUCAÇÃO

Staff Software Engineer

2023 - Present

- · Led a team of five engineers in migrating multiple legacy services to well-architected, scalable microservices.
- · Achieved over \$80K/year in cost savings through AWS FinOps initiatives optimizing legacy services.
- Designed, developed, and maintained microservices with a strong foundation in software engineering principles and best practices.

Senior Software Engineer

2022 - 2023

- Technical leadership and development in JavaScript/TypeScript, Node.js, React, AWS, and various frameworks.
- Developing and maintaining 6+ applications across different domains.

Technologies: Javascript, Typescript, NodeJS, NextJS, React, AWS and SQL.

MB LABS

Tech Lead

2022 - 2023

- Technical leadership, including mentoring junior developers and providing guidance.
- Code reviews, project planning and estimations, organizing timelines and deliveries for clients.
- Lead developer and tech leader for a full-scale education application.

Software Engineer

2020 - 2022

- Designing and developing robust web applications with a focus on scalability and performance.
- Full-stack expertise, leveraging front-end and back-end technologies to drive innovation and deliver exceptional user experiences.
- Contributed to various applications, including for Versa Fuel, a geolocation startup built with Node, is (backend), React (dashboard), and React Native (client-side).

Technologies: Javascript, Typescript, NodeJS, React Native, React, Angular, SQL, AWS.

BOX IT

2018 - 2019

Full Stack Web Developer

- Developed and maintained CRM (Customer Relationship Management) and ERP (Enterprise Resource Planning) systems.
- Tech stack: Vue.js (JavaScript) for the front end and Laravel (PHP) for the back end.
- Built custom institutional websites tailored to specific business needs.

 $\textbf{Technologies}: JavaSript \cdot NodeJS \cdot Laravel \cdot VueJS \cdot SQL \ (MySQL) \cdot Git$

EDUCATION

University of Brasília – School of Science and Technology in Engineering (UnB FCTE) B.S. Software Engineering

2018 - 2024

SKILLS

C • JavaScript

TypeScript

React

• Git

NoSQL

Problem • I Solving

NodeJS

NextAWS

• SQL

CI/CD

Software Architecture

Microservices